This is how guards are placed in the City Owner's Mansion.
這是花垣城城主府各處部署情況
I'll go in first and arrange things.
到時候我先進去安排
An hour later,
等半個時辰
you go in with soldiers and help me out.
你帶人與我裡應外合
Within a short time,
過不了多久
I'll be able to deploy
我就能重新調動
the City Guards of Huayuan again.
花垣城的護城軍了
(Defense Map of Huayuan City) With Your Highness' assistance,
有二郡主相助
I'm in my element.
韓某如魚得水
Your Highness,
啟稟郡主
the Crown Princess is here.
少城主來了
What is she here for?
她來幹什麼
Young Master, let's go.
少君 請
Let her in.
讓她進來吧
Yes.
是
So
原來
you serve Chen Chuchu.
你是陳楚楚的人
No wonder you repeatedly tried to kill Chen Qianqian
難怪之前在威猛山屢次設計
on Weimeng Mountain.
陷害陳芊芊的性命
The Crown Princess is immoral.
少城主失德
She doesn't deserve to be the owner of Huayuan City.
不配做花垣城的主人
Do you know why I came?
知道今日我為何來找你嗎
How am I supposed to know
我怎麼知道少城主今日來
what you came for?
所為何事
Is it to have a heart-to-heart talk with me?
該不會是 姐妹談心的吧
Did you kill Lu Peng?
陸鵬是不是你殺的
Wasn't he killed by Lin Qi?
陸鵬不是林七殺的嗎
You exiled her in person.
三妹親口判了林七流放
Why are you accusing me now?
怎麼又扣到我的頭上來
Did you kill him or not?
到底是不是你殺的
Lu Peng witnessed your argument with Mother.
陸鵬目睹了你跟母親發生爭執
Your reason to kill him is more plausible.
你比林七更有理由要殺他
Speaking of that,
要這麼說
weren't you always against
三妹你也一直不想
Lu Peng marrying Yuanyuan?
陸鵬和沅沅成婚
You have a reason to kill him, too.
那你也有理由殺他
It's indeed you.
果然是你
Now that you had reached a conclusion,
三妹既然有了決斷
why did you come and ask me?
為何還要來問我
Chen Chuchu,
陳楚楚
if you didn't want him to blab about it,
你若是不想讓他亂說話
you could just threaten him.
你嚇唬嚇唬他就行了
Why must you kill him?
為什麼一定要殺人呢
So now you know life is precious.
你這個時候知道人命可貴了
When you wronged Young Master Han
三妹冤枉韓少君
and confined him for life,
將他終生圈禁的時候
did it cross your mind that life was precious?
可有想過人命可貴
Treating him like that
你這樣待他
is even crueler than killing him.
比殺了他還殘忍
What did you mention Han Shuo for?
你提韓爍做什麼
Certainly,
也是
an insignificant Young Master
區區一個玄虎城少君
of Xuanhu City is just
在三妹眼裡
a plaything to you.
不過是一介玩物而已
Without Han Shuo,
沒了韓爍
you still have Minister Pei.
你還有裴司學
I heard that
我聽說
after Young Master Han left,
自從韓少君走後
music was played
三妹的月璃府裡
and songs were sung
是夜夜笙歌
every night in your mansion.
熱鬧得很啊
I finally know
我算是知道
why Mother would fall ill.
母親為什麼被你氣生病了
If I had heart disease,
若是我有心疾
I would suffer an attack right now!
我現在就要被你氣得發病了
Didn't you hear it all?
都聽見了吧
You are not important
你在她心裡
at all to her.
一點分量都沒有
Watch the Second Princess closely.
看好二郡主
No one's allowed to enter or leave Xingzi Mansion.
任何人都不得出入星梓府
Yes.
是
The hero left.
男主走了
The heroine turned into a villain.
女主黑化
The supporting roles are dead.
配角也炮灰了
No Wi-Fi.
沒有無線網絡
No phones.
沒有手機
Only distress is left.
人生就只剩下苦悶了
I sent Han Shuo away
攔住了韓爍
and stopped Xuanhu from conquering Huayuan.
阻止了玄虎滅花垣
But my story also stopped here.
可我的故事也就停在這兒了
No progress at all.
毫無進展
Is Huayuan heading for its doom?
咱們花垣是不是要完蛋了
The Crown Princess is always like that.
你看少城主整天那樣
She's simply hopeless.
簡直 就是個廢人
Stop drinking.
別喝了
If you really miss Han Shuo,
你如果實在想念韓爍
you can absolve him
可以赦他無罪
and order him to come back.
重新傳召讓他回城
Don't make yourself suffer.
為何要為難自己
Han Shuo can never
韓爍這輩子
return to Xuanhu or Huayuan.
都不能回玄虎和花垣了
I messed it up.
都是我搞砸的
If Lin Qi hadn't died,
若是林七還沒有死
there could be room for changing everything.
那一切可能還有迴轉的餘地
Then he and I would
我就可以和他
be able to be together forever
一直在一起
and didn't have to leave each other.
不用分開了
I'll drink the rest of the wine
那剩下的酒
with you.
我陪你喝
Han Shuo.
韓爍
I'm sorry.
對不起
I said I didn't like you before.
我之前說我不喜歡你
I was lying.
是騙你的
I want to be with you forever so much.
我多希望我們一直在一起
Me, too.
我也希望
Bai Ji.
白芨
Young Master,
少君
you said you were going to check defense of the city.
您剛剛說的是去探查城防的
Of course I came to see clearly
自然是來看看清楚
so that we can act tonight.
好在今夜行動
Your Majesty.
城主
I hear
我聽說
Qianqian went to the Music and Dance Academy again.
今天芊芊又去了教坊司
Looks like this child
看來這孩子
is still stricken by love.
還是為情所困哪
Sangqi, to be honest,
桑奇 平心而論
Chuchu is fitter than Qianqian
楚楚比芊芊
to be the City Owner.
更合適城主之位
Your Majesty,
城主
these two princesses
兩位郡主
are both pillars of the city.
皆是城之棟樑
The Second Princess is brave and resourceful
這二郡主有勇有謀
and the Crown Princess is flexible.
少城主機智變通
They both have their strong points.
她們兩個是各有千秋啊
But after Han Shuo left,
你看 自從韓爍走了以後
Qianqian
芊芊
is no longer the person who loves her city.
哪有一個為城為民考量的樣子
I'll reconsider my decision.
這事 我還是再考慮考慮吧
Although Chuchu talked back to me,
雖然上次楚楚頂撞了我
after that matter,
但歷經此事
she'll be steadier
她也會沉穩許多
and less impetuous.
不再那麼急躁了
She's still cut out for it.
還是一個好苗子
I don't need her filial affection.
我不求她孝順我
She's not my own child, anyway.
本來就不是親生的
I only need her
我只求她能對花垣城
to be kind to Huayuan people.
對百姓子民好一些
So I think
楚楚呢
I'll lift her confinement.
解了她的禁足吧
Your Majesty!
報
Someone has besieged the city and is attacking your mansion.
有人圍城 進攻城主府邸
What?
什麼
When I was in a coma,
我昏迷這段時間
did Qianqian confiscate Chuchu's flower token?
芊芊可曾收走楚楚的花符
No.
沒有
The Crown Princess considered their relation
少城主顧及姐妹情分
and only confined her.
所以 只下令禁足
What?
什麼
Your Majesty.
城主
Let's go back.
快回去吧
Chen Chuchu.
陳楚楚
What nonsense did Meng Guo write again?
這孟過又寫了什麼廢話
The weather was sunny.
天氣晴朗
I was caught in a sandstorm again.
塞外多風沙
Everywhere...
無處
So much nonsense.
廢話真多
The sandstorm was over. I lost track of them.
風沙過去 跟丟
How could he lose track of him?!
跟丟了可還行
Oh, he's here.
這 這不在這兒呢
You... come and help me to my bed. Come.
你 來 你扶我一把 來
How long are you gonna sleep?
你想睡多久
If I can,
如果可以的話
I wanna sleep until the end of the play.
我就想睡到全劇終
I'll wait for you however long it takes.
你想睡多久我都等你
If I say I did it
我說我之前這麼做
for your own good,
都是為了你好
will you believe me?
你能信嗎
Go on, please.
少城主請講
Forget it. Even I myself don't believe it.
算了 我自己都不信
Come. Guard this place.
來人 嚴加看守
What... what's going on?
怎 怎麼了
What's happening outside?
外面怎麼了
Young Master, we've besieged the City Owner's Mansion.
少君 已經圍住了城主府
You besieged the city?
你圍城了
I asked you not to make so much noise
不是讓你們小聲點
and wake her up.
別吵到她睡覺
I'm sorry.
屬下知錯
When I was on my way to exile,
流放路上 我本來想著
I thought even if you were just a bit sad,
哪怕你能有一絲絲的難過
I would forgive you.
我都會原諒你
But what I saw was...
但我看到的卻是
No, I...
不是 我那個
Do... do you know what acting happy is?
你 你懂不懂什麼叫作強顏歡笑
I have been really sad.
我真的特別難過
I can even cry now.
我現在都能哭出來
Then I'll think you were shedding
那樣我會誤以為少城主是
tears of happiness.
喜極而泣
No.
不
It... it's just about comedy.
這 這些都是喜劇效果
Actually I think the plot is still
其實我覺得我們現在的劇情還是
quite campy so far.
比較狗血的
During the thirteen days I was away,
離開的十三天
I missed you every day.
我每一天都在想你
What did you miss me for?
想我幹什麼呀
Young Master.
少君
This is a gift for you.
這是給你的禮物
You didn't have to.
太客氣了
You could just come without any gifts.
來就來 送什麼禮物呀
What...
這
Your Highness,
少城主
drink one every day.
每天喝一瓶
What... what are these?
這 這都是些什麼呀
Should be honey water.
應該都是蜂蜜吧
Right.
對
If you don't drink them,
如果你不喝
your mother will have no medicine to take.
你母親就沒有藥喝了
She is in my hands now.
如今 你母親捏在我手裡
Are they all honey water?
真的都是蜂蜜
One contains Soul Missing Powder.
有一瓶是斷魂散
Which one?
哪一瓶啊
Guess.
你猜
Try one now, Your Highness.
現在少城主就試用一瓶吧
No big deal. I'll just die here.
大不了我就不回家了
Your mother's medicine.
你母親的藥
It's not honey water.
這不是蜂蜜水
It's bitter melon juice.
這是苦瓜汁 你
Confine the Crown Princess.
把少城主圈禁起來
Yes.
是
What did I do those things for?
你說我這都是圖什麼呀
I tried so hard to prevent
玄虎滅花垣
Xuanhu from taking over Huayuan
這事我左躲右躲
and it still happened.
結果還是沒躲過去
Order from the higher authorities.
上頭有令
Close the gate. No one's allowed to enter or leave the city.
關閉城門 出入禁止
Let us out.
快 快放我們出去
Young Master Han is back.
韓少君殺回來了
Soldiers from Xuanhu City are everywhere.
全都是玄虎城的士兵
If we stay here,
在這兒待下去
we'll all have to die.
我們都得陪葬
Let us out. Let us out.
快放我們出去 放我們出去
What about the Princess Royal?
大郡主呢
What's going on in Risheng Mansion?
日晟府呢
Risheng Mansion has been besieged.
日晟府已經被包圍了
It's dangerous there. Flee right now.
凶多吉少 趕快逃吧
Let us out.
讓我們出去
(Quietness and Elegance) Don't touch that, you bastard.
混賬 不許碰那個
Will?
遺書
Your Highness has been lame for years
這大郡主瘸了十幾年
and has always been writing wills.
動不動就寫遺書
How come you have never even
怎的寫到今時今日
tried to kill yourself once?
也不見尋一回短見
Let's go.
走 走
Your Highness.
郡主
Su Mu.
蘇沐
Your Highness, please get up.
郡主 郡主快起來
Zi Nian, take it.
梓年 拿著
Your Highness,
郡主
were you hurt?
有沒有傷到
Now you're back.
這個時候你倒是回來了
You really flatter yourself.
你真的是太自以為是了
I thought you said
你不是說
you didn't like me.
你不喜歡我嗎
I've changed.
今日不同往日
I didn't like you before
往日不喜歡
but now I do.
現在又喜歡了
That's to say
這麼說
you admit it?
你是承認了
You have feelings for me.
你心裡頭有我
Don't you mind that you're a musician now?
你不在乎自己樂人的身份了
The city has been captured.
這大難當前
It doesn't matter who I am now.
還在乎什麼身份
But you may be in trouble, too.
可是我怕連累你
I, Su Mu,
小人
was fortunate to be liked by Your Highness.
承蒙大郡主不棄
From now on, I'll stay with you
從今往後必陪侍左右
until death do us apart.
生死不離
I would rather you didn't admit it.
我倒是寧願你不認
Now we're like
現在好了
a couple on the run.
搞得我們像一對亡命鴛鴦
Your Highness.
郡主
These are all your wishes.
這都是大郡主的心願
Now most of them have
如今被燒的
gone up in smoke.
不剩下什麼了
Luckily this one is still here.
還好這張還在
Your Highness,
郡主
look. To win someone's heart.
看 願得一心人
Young Master Han Shuo of Xuanhu viciously attacked
玄虎城少君韓爍狼子野心
Huayuan City after Qianqian humiliated and exiled him.
被三妹羞辱流放後 反攻回城
Han Shuo rebelled but I'm still here.
韓爍反了 但女兒還在
I've sent guards to protect your mansion.
女兒已經派人守好城主府邸
You'll be safe, Mother.
定會保母親安全
You're indeed my good girl.
果然是我教出的好女兒
I've taught you well.
是我教得好
With you,
有你在
I'll rest easy.
我就放心了
Where's Qianqian?
芊芊呢
Is she in Han Shuo's hands
是在韓爍手裡
or Chuchu's?
還是在楚楚手裡
She's with Young Master Han.
在韓少君手裡
The first thing he did after he came back
韓少君回城的第一件事
was surrounding the Crown Princess.
就是把少城主圍了起來
Just surrounded her?
只是圍了起來
Yes, he just surrounded her.
對 只是圍了起來
Good. That's a good thing.
好 那就好
Yes. If Her Highness is with Young Master Han,
是了 少城主在少君手裡
she'll be safe and sound.
那就是安然無恙
Her Majesty doesn't feel well today
城主今日身感不適
and there are city affairs to handle.
又逢政事繁雜
The Second Princess, Chen Chuchu, is promising,
二郡主陳楚楚年輕有為
brave and resourceful. She can be of great use.
有勇有謀 堪為大用
Thus, the Second Princess, Chen Chuchu, is specially
特指二郡主陳楚楚
assigned to act in the City Owner's stead.
代為處理政務
If Her Majesty is not well,
城主不適
it should be the Crown Princess who fills in.
該由少城主暫代
Your Highness,
二郡主
isn't it against the rules for you to meddle
貿然插手花垣城政務
in affairs of Huayuan City?
是否逾矩
Soldiers.
來人
The Second Princess Chen Chuchu
二郡主陳楚楚
disregards rules set by the ancestors.
罔顧祖宗規矩
Does anyone else object?
還有異議嗎
Where's Sangqi? Ask him to send...
桑奇在哪兒 讓桑奇出來傳
Anyone else?
還有嗎
Minister Liu, you always put
劉司銀平時處處
in a word for the Second Princess.
替二郡主說好話
Why didn't you step forward
此時怎麼不站出來
and congratulate Her Highness now?
恭賀二郡主得償所願
Leave.
散了
You can't go in. You can't go in.
您不能進 不能進呀
Go away.
讓開
It's not too late for you to repent now.
你現在回頭還來得及
What made you say that, Minister Pei?
裴司學何出此言
Answer me.
我問你
Why did Han Shuo come back?
韓爍為什麼會回來
The disappearance of Su Mu
教坊司蘇沐失蹤案
was fabricated by Chen Qianqian.
乃陳芊芊自導自演出來的
Han Shuo is never guilty.
本來就不怪韓爍
Let me ask you again.
我再問你
Are the guards who besieged the City Owner's Mansion
圍困城主府的護城軍
your men
到底是你的人
or Han Shuo's?
還是韓爍的人
Chuchu,
楚楚
I know you won't take my words seriously.
我知道你不會將我的話放在心上
But I still need to say this.
可我還是要說
Everything you want
你想要的一切
would belong to you.
本來都可以是屬於你的
But if you grab it yourself,
但是你要是先動手搶了
it'll no longer be yours.
就再也不是你的了
Now that it's mine,
既然是我的
it's just a matter of time
早點得到 晚點得到
before I get them.
只是時間問題
Don't be bothered, Minister Pei.
不勞裴司學
Oh, no. You're not the Minister of Education now.
不 您現在已經不是司學了
I still call you Minister Pei
我還尊稱您一句裴司學
just for the late Minister of Defense Pei's sake.
不過是給已故裴司軍的臉面而已
The late Minister of Defense. If my mother knows...
裴司軍 母親若見你如此
Young Master Han.
韓少君
You have had a tiring day.
二郡主今天也累了
Let's discuss what to do tomorrow.
咱們明日再商議以後的事
Young Master Han
這韓少君
was uneasy when he saw Minister Pei.
怎麼見著裴司學就心神不寧的
Does he still have feelings
怕不是韓少君心中
for the Crown Princess?
還惦記著少城主吧
Han Shuo is vengeful.
韓爍睚眥必報
If Pei Heng goes to save Chen Qianqian,
裴恆去找陳芊芊
he won't be able to help her
不僅無法幫她
but infuriate Han Shuo instead.
還會激起韓爍的怒氣
Don't go in, Mr. Pei.
公子三思
You don't have any real powers or forces.
您沒有實權 調不動兵馬
You're no match for Han Shuo
單憑咱家的府軍
with our guards alone.
根本無力與現在的韓爍抗衡
If you barge in now,
這樣硬闖
you'll be courting death.
無異於是以卵擊石啊
Even if you worry about the Crown Princess,
您再擔心少城主
you still need to think twice.
也要從長計議呀
I have no idea how Han Shuo will treat Qianqian.
不知道韓爍會如何對待芊芊
I must save her.
我必須要救她
Mr. Pei,
公子
you can't save Her Highness alone.
你一個人是救不了少城主的
I must try even if I can't.
救不了我也要救
Mr. Pei. Mr. Pei.
公子 公子
Mr. Pei.
公子
If you keep doing this,
你這樣做
you'll never win Qianqian's heart.
永遠得不到芊芊的心
But you can't even have her body.
可你連人都得不到
If you hurt her,
你傷害一個人
you'll be unworthy of her affection for you.
只會辜負她對你的情意
Her affection?
她的情意
What about mine?
那我的情意呢
You've been divorced.
你們已經和離了
I'm taking Qianqian away.
我要帶芊芊走
Mr. Pei. Mr. Pei. Mr. Pei.
公子 公子 公子
Let go of me. Mr. Pei.
你們放開我 公子
Try it.
來啊
Her divorce letter
什麼休書 和離
only complies with rules of Huayuan City.
那都是你們花垣城的規矩
Now we'll obey those of Xuanhu City.
現在得按我們玄虎城的
She's my wife.
她是我的女人
She's staying with me forever.
她這輩子都走不了
Pei Heng.
裴恆
Are you okay?
沒事吧
Stop.
住手
Qianqian.
芊芊
What are you doing?
幹什麼
Han Shuo, let go of her.
韓爍 你放開她
What are you doing, Han Shuo?
韓爍 你幹什麼
Put me down, Han Shuo.
韓爍 你放我下來
Let go.
放開我
Let go of me, Han Shuo.
你放開我 韓爍
Qianqian.
芊芊
Qianqian! Qianqian!
芊芊 芊芊
Go.
走
Qianqian!
芊芊
Please let Qianqian go, Young Master Han!
請韓少君放過芊芊
Han Shuo.
韓爍
You and Pei Heng were really a pitiful sight.
你和裴恆倒是心疼彼此
You begged me for each other.
互相為對方求情
What are you doing?
你幹什麼
Stay away from me.
你別過來
I once loved you,
從前我愛你
respected you and cherished you.
敬你 惜你
And you
可是
were so unworthy.
你不值得
Don't you dare, Han Shuo.
韓爍 你敢
Of course I dare.
我敢啊
And no one will stop us now.
而且現在沒有人會來擋住我們了
Listen, Han Shuo.
韓爍 我告訴你
Nothing forcibly done is going to be agreeable.
強扭的瓜不甜的
You won't know for sure
甜不甜的
before you try.
啃一口不就知道了
Help!
救命
Help! Help!
救命 救命
Han Shuo, don't do it.
韓爍 不要
Han Shuo, don't be like this. Han Shuo.
韓爍 你別這樣 韓爍
Help! Help! Go away!
救命 救命 給我滾開
Han Shuo.
韓爍
Han Shuo, don't be like this. I'm scared.
韓爍 你別這樣 我害怕
I'm really scared.
我真的害怕了
What a spoilsport.
掃興
Huayuan women
花垣女人
really disappoint people.
不過如此
She indeed can't do Kung Fu anymore.
她的確武功盡失
She just never speaks a true word.
嘴裡真是一句真話都沒有
But what was I doing?
但我又在幹什麼呢
Han Shuo,
韓爍
you beast.
你這個畜生
I was doing what a couple will do with my wife.
我與我娘子行夫妻之實
Did I break any rules?
哪裡逾矩
And you are still here.
倒是你 還守在這裡
Did you enjoy Chen Qianqian's yells?
陳芊芊的叫聲好聽嗎
You don't love her.
你不愛她
You don't love her at all!
你根本就不愛她
Love!
愛
You love her. Does she care?
你愛她 她有感覺嗎
Chen Qianqian only loves herself.
陳芊芊她只愛自己
She doesn't love anyone else.
誰都不愛
I'll treat her the same way
她曾經如何對我
she once treated me.
我就如何對她
Nobody gets away with doing that to me.
我韓爍有債必償
You'd better give up as soon as possible.
我勸你還是早點死心
If I find that you try
要是再讓我發現
to steal my wife again,
你對她有所圖謀
I won't be kind to you.
我對你不客氣
Escort Minister Pei back to his mansion.
送裴司學回府
What's that look of yours?
你什麼表情啊
You're so good at saying hurtful words
您說狠話的時候倒是厲害
but once you saw Her Highness, your heart melted.
一見到少城主心就軟了
You came out within such a short time.
這還不到半炷香就出來了
If you really can't do it,
您要實在下不去手的話
shall I help you?
要不我幫幫您
You help me?
你幫我
Do what you failed to do
您在威猛山欠下的
on Weimeng Mountain.
現在補回來
Get lost.
滾
Come back.
回來
Replace everyone
按照城防圖
with our soldiers according to the defense map.
全部替換成我們的人手
Chen Chuchu is not reliable.
陳楚楚不可信
Mr. Pei. Mr. Pei.
公子 公子
Mr. Pei.
公子
Han Shuo, do you think
韓爍 你以為
I'll give up Qianqian like this?
我就會這麼放棄芊芊嗎
Your Highness, are you okay?
少城主 沒事吧
Didn't you see it?
你覺得呢
I shouldn't have cared about that beast.
當初我就不該管那畜生
I should've let Han Shuo die.
不管韓爍死活
I just shouldn't have cared about him.
我就不該管他 我就
Why don't you give in to Young Master Han?
你要麼從了韓少君吧
What did you say?
你說什麼
When Young Master Han was exiled,
韓少君被流放的時候
you thought about him all the time.
你是朝思暮想地想著人家
Now he's back
現在一個大活人回來了
and stands in front of you,
就站在你的面前
don't you also want to be with him?
你從了他也是從了你自己
And he'll stop besieging the city.
還能解圍城之困
Won't all be well, then?
這不兩大歡喜嗎
Is the current Han Shuo
現在的韓爍
still the old one?
還是以前的韓爍嗎
Now he's an-eye-for-an-eye Shuo.
現在的韓爍就是有仇必報爍
He's an an-eye-for-an-eye demon.
他現在就是個有仇必報的大魔王
An... An-eye-for-an-eye Shuo.
有 有仇必報爍
But if you'd rather die than give in
你要是寧死不從的話
and infuriate Han Shuo,
把韓爍惹怒了
the Second Princess will be the City Owner
二郡主繼任城主之位
and no one will protect us.
就再也沒人護著咱們了
I think our... our lives are more important.
我覺得 保 保命重要
Chuchu is going to be the City Owner?
楚楚要繼任城主
Yesterday Zi Zhu announced an order from the City Owner
昨天梓竹在議事廳宣佈城主令
and said Her majesty was sick
說城主生病了
and let the Second Princess act in her stead.
讓二郡主代理城主之位
I don't know if it's true
也不知道說得真的假的
but everyone is saying
外面都在傳
the Second Princess will succeed the City Owner soon.
過幾天 二郡主就會繼任城主
Chuchu succeeds the City Owner.
楚楚繼任城主
The sun and the moon shine at the same time. The heavenly gate opens.
日月同輝 天門大開
It's getting back to the plot.
劇情回來了
What are you talking about, Your Highness?
少城主 您說什麼呢
That's the sign of a good ruler coming down.
日月同輝是明主降世的祥兆
The Second Princess is not worthy.
二郡主這樣的 不配
In that case,
這樣一來
I'll be able to wake up and go home.
我倒是可以醒過來回家了
But Han Shuo dies shortly after Chuchu
可是楚楚繼任城主跟韓爍的死
succeeds the City Owner.
也就是前後腳的事
Now Xuanhu has besieged
如今玄虎城圍城的情節
Huayuan City.
也照樣發生了
What if Han Shuo actually dies
萬一按照劇情的推進
according to the plot?
韓爍真的死了可怎麼辦
No.
不行
I can't let Chuchu be the City Owner.
我不能讓楚楚繼任城主
Quickly. Go in. Go in.
快快快 進去進去
Look. Men from Xuanhu are ferocious.
看 玄虎城的男人可真凶啊
Your Highness, choose one.
少城主 選一瓶吧
Well,
不
there were ten yesterday.
昨天還是十選一
How come there are only five today?
今天為什麼就變成五選一了
Isn't it more likely that I'll choose
這樣 我中獎的機率
the poisonous one?
不就更大了嗎
Young Master said this was funnier.
少君說了 這樣更好玩
Funnier?
更好玩
He thinks it's funnier.
他倒是覺得好玩了
Has he considered
他有沒有考慮過
the feelings of the player?
玩家的遊戲體驗
Won't...
那
won't there be only two tomorrow?
那明天是不是就只有兩瓶了
It all depends on Young Master's mood.
一切都看少君心情
Han Shuo,
韓爍
you are the obstacle on my way home.
你就是我回家路上的攔路虎
I can't let him torture me like this.
我不能坐以待斃
I need to counter-attack.
我要主動出擊
Exciting.
刺激
Your Highness.
少城主
Oh dear. Oh dear. Oh dear.
完了 完了 完了
Oh dear. Oh dear.
完了 完了
Young Master. Young Master. Oh dear.
少君 完了完了
What's she up to again?
她這又是鬧哪一齣啊
Her Highness had a stomachache
少城主喝了之後
after she drank it.
疼得死去活來的
Soy sauce, vinegar, honey water, scallion juice and liquor.
醬油 醋 蜂蜜 蔥汁 白酒
Which one can make her stomach ache?
你說 哪樣能讓她腹痛不止
But she drank all of them.
可是她把五瓶都喝了
You...
你
why didn't you stop her?
你怎麼不攔著她呀
I tried to
我攔了呀
but I failed.
沒攔住
She did that
她鬧這麼一出
in order to see the Princess Royal, right?
是不是想見大郡主
I think...
我覺著
It's aching.
疼啊
Help, Yuanyuan.
長姐救我
It's killing me.
不行了
So painful.
好痛
It's killing me. It's killing me.
不行了 不行了 快
Quick. It's killing me.
快點 不行了
Quick.
快
Quickly.
快點
So painful.
好痛
So... so painful.
好 好痛
God, it aches so much.
好疼 天哪
Just now I drank the same things as you.
剛剛我和少城主喝了一樣的東西
How come I'm alright
為什麼我沒事
and your stomach aches so much?
少城主卻腹痛不止
That's because you're strong.
那是因為少君身強力壯
I'm too weak.
我自然是比不上
Quick, send for Yuanyuan. Quickly.
快 請長姐來給我看看 快點
Don't worry.
放心
To be on the safe side,
為了保險起見
I have sent for a doctor.
我還是請了大夫
Doc...
大
Will be here soon.
一會兒就到
That's not okay.
大夫不行
Yuanyuan is the best doctor
整個花垣城
in the whole Huayuan City.
就長姐醫術最好
Send for her. Quick.
請長姐來給我看吧 快
You're so seriously ill.
少城主病成這樣
Don't you also want to see your mother?
是不是還想見母親
Shall I ask the City Owner to come as well?
要不我一併把城主也請來
If you do that,
如果可以的話
it'll be the best.
自然是最好的
Chen Qianqian,
陳芊芊
don't try to fool me.
別跟我耍花腔
I won't let you see
我是不會讓你見她們
any one of them.
任何一個人的
Now that you don't want to see the doctor,
既然你不想看大夫
keep aching, then.
那就繼續疼著吧
Han Shuo!
韓爍
I'm like this and you're still not helping me?
我都這樣了你都不管我
Aren't you well?
少城主這不挺好的
Stay here.
好好待著
Don't think about escaping.
別總想著逃出去
When you were away,
你不在的時候
I missed you every day and every moment.
我日日思念你 時刻掛念你
Should you treat me like this?
你回來你就這樣對我
Young Master, a group of musicians
少君 有一幫樂人
came singing and playing.
敲敲打打地找上門來
They said the Crown Princess invited
說之前少城主三天兩頭
them over almost every day before
便請他們入府作陪
and now she doesn't do that anymore.
現在不找他們了
They miss the Crown Princess.
他們思念少城主
Almost every day.
三天兩頭
When you missed me,
少城主掛念我的時候
you needed musicians to play music to you.
還需要樂人彈曲作陪
No, Han Shuo. There must be some misunderstanding.
不是 韓爍 指定是有誤會
They... they slandered me.
他 他們血口噴人
Ask... ask them to go back.
你 你讓他們回去
Let them in.
讓他們進來
Otherwise, Your Highness will miss them so much
省得少城主朝思暮想
and get away to see them.
還得逃出去見他們
You got it wrong.
我沒有
Han Shuo, you've really got it wrong. You...
韓爍 我真的沒有 你
Why on earth did you come here?
你們來湊什麼熱鬧啊
Han Shuo was in a fit of anger.
這韓爍正在氣頭上
Didn't you add fuel to the fire?
這不烈火澆油嗎
We came to play music to you.
我們來給少城主彈曲聽啊
I'm so distressed now. I don't wanna listen to it.
我今天煩得很 我不想聽曲
Pei...
裴
You need music more when you're distressed.
心煩 才更要聽
Who told me
是誰告訴我
music could relieve my distress?
琴聲可以消解苦悶
What are you doing here?
你怎麼來了
I came to get you out of here.
我來救你出去
Get...
救
How are you going to do that?
要怎麼救我出去啊
You're so furtive.
鬼鬼祟祟
Bai Ji.
白芨
Look at me.
看我
Listen carefully.
聽好了
The Crown Princess wants to eat
我們少城主今天想吃
roast duck and goose,
燒花鴨 燒子鵝
pig bladder with pine nuts, aired meat and sausage,
松花小肚 晾肉香腸
crystal and amber pig elbows,
水晶肘子 蜜蠟肘子
blanched and fried three kinds of meat.
汆三樣 爆三樣
If you don't want me to name more things,
你要不想繼續背
go and get them ready now.
趕緊過去去準備
Say them again.
再說一遍
Roast duck and goose,
燒花鴨 燒子鵝
pig bladder with pine nuts, aired meat and sausage.
松花小肚 晾肉香腸
Okay, okay.
行行行
I'll go right now.
我這就去準備
I've got to be grateful that Bai Ji is
得感謝白芨這種
someone who can never do things well
成事不足 敗事有餘的人設
and you can speak.
還有你這嘴皮子
Luckily Han Shuo is out.
幸好韓爍不在府裡
I speak so fluently.
那我這嘴皮子多溜啊
How's my mother now?
母親現在怎麼樣
Her Majesty is under house arrest.
城主被軟禁在府中
Yuanyuan and Su Mu
沅沅與蘇沐
are also locked in.
也一併被關著
They're alright for the moment.
他們暫且無事
I'm really sorry.
真是難為你了
You had to disguise yourself as a musician.
讓你扮成樂人的樣子
I once thought it was shameful to please women
我曾以取悅女人為恥
but now I think
可如今我卻覺得
it's also great to help the woman I love
能幫到心愛的女人
and make her laugh.
令她開懷一笑也不錯
Pei Heng.
裴恆
I know.
我知道
I shouldn't talk about that now.
現在不是說這些的時候
Did Han Shuo make things difficult for you again?
韓爍有沒有再為難你
No. He's quite nice to me.
沒有 韓爍對我挺好的
After what he has done,
都這時候了
you still defended him.
你居然還替他說話
It's a long story.
這事說來話長
I'm to blame.
是我對不起他
I forced him to be like that.
把他逼到了這一步
Your Highness.
少城主
Butler.
管家